http://www.animationmentor.com/legal/privacy/

Courses
Character Animation CoursesAnimation BasicsBody MechanicsAdvanced Body MechanicsIntroduction to ActingAdvanced ActingPolishing and PortfolioWorkshops OverviewWorkshops for Beginners
Maya Workshop: Animation Basics2D Animation for Beginners
Intermediate Animation
2D Animation: Walk Cycles and Character Movement
Advanced Animation
Cartoony Animation for 3D AnimatorsPrevisualization Basics for Animators
Creature Animation
Creature Animation: LocomotionCreature Animation: Fight or Flight
Game Animation
Game Animation FundamentalsGame Animation Combat Attacks
Storyboarding
Storyboarding FundamentalsIntermediate Storyboarding
Concept Art
Introduction to Digital PaintingVisual Development: Principles of Design
Introduction to 3D Character ModelingLectures On Demand
Admissions
Admissions OverviewHow to Apply & RegisterWhy Animation MentorDo I Qualify?Tuition and Start DatesTuition BreakdownAdvanced PlacementStudent LoansRepeat a ClassInternational StudentsCorporate Discount ProgramGet More InformationCommon QuestionsOnline Campus TourApply Now
Rigs
Animation Characters and RigsFree Animation Rig
Student Life
OverviewAlumniStudent ServicesCareer ServicesStudent Showcases
Mentors
OverviewMentor Roster
About
OverviewMission and ValuesPartnersCareersPress RoomContact Us
Resources
WebinarseBooksPodcastsTips & Tricks11 Second Club — eCritiquesMerchandise
Blog
Get More Information
Apply Now
Privacy Policy
Effective date: May 25, 2018
AnimationMentor.com is serious about protecting your online privacy. This Privacy Statement explains our views and practices concerning privacy, and how they may pertain to you as a user of our website.
Next Education, LLC (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the Service, as defined below.
AnimationMentor.com is serious about protecting your online privacy. This Privacy Statement explains our views and practices concerning privacy, and how they may pertain to you as a user of our website, products and subscriptions.
This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.
We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from www.animationmentor.com
Definitions:
•Service
Service means the website and services available at the following websites: www.animationmentor.com, registration.animationmentor.com, blog.animationmentor.com, campus.animationmentor.com, support.animationmentor.com, and students.animationmentor.com.
•Cookies
Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device).
•Data Controller
Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.
•Data Processors (or Service Providers)
Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller. We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.
•Data Subject (or User)
Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.
What information do we collect?
We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.
•We collect information from you when you register on our site, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form.
•When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address or phone number. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.
•The Service may allow you to upload files and other content, which you may then elect to share with others (“Shared Files”).
Types of Data Collected
“Personal Data” means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data). We have grouped the different kinds of Personal Data we collect as follows:
•Identity Data may include first name, last name, company name, website URL, and other demographic data that you provide to Next Education, LLC.
•Contact Data includes billing address, email address and telephone numbers.
•Financial Data includes bank account and payment card details.
•Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
•Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
•Profile Data includes your username and password, purchases made by you, your preferences, feedback and survey responses.
•Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
•Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.
•Where we need to collect Personal Data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us, but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.
Do we use cookies and tracking data?
Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.
•We use cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.
•Do we disclose any information to outside parties?
•We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect others or ours rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.
•Third party links
•Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer links to third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.
Removing Cookies
You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.
Examples of Cookies we use:
•Session Cookies. We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
•Preference Cookies. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
•Security Cookies. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
What do we use your information for?
Next Education, LLC uses the collected data for various purposes:
•To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
•To process transactions
•Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.
•To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
•To provide and maintain our Service
•To notify you about changes to our Service
•To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
•To provide customer support
•To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
•To monitor the usage of our Service
•To detect, prevent and address technical issues
•To send periodic emails
•The email address you provide for order processing, will only be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order.
•If you decide to opt-in to our mailing list, you will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.
•To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information
Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
•Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
•Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
•Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
We have set out below, in table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/Activity
Type of data
Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest
To register you as a new customer
(a) Identity(b) Contact
Performance of a contract with you
To process and deliver your order including:(a) Manage payments, fees and charges(b) Collect and recover money owed to us
(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Financial(d) Transaction(e) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)
To manage our relationship with you which will include:(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy(b) Asking you for feedback
(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Marketing and Communications
(a) Performance of a contract with you(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)
(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Technical
(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganization or group restructuring exercise)(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Usage(e) Marketing and Communications(f) Technical
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
(a) Technical(b) Usage
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you
(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Technical(d) Usage(e) Profile
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)
Retention of Data
Next Education, LLC will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.
Next Education, LLC
will also retain Usage Data and Technical Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data and Technical Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.
Transfer of Data
Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.
If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.
Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.
How do we protect your information?
Next Education, LLC will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.
•We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.
•After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.
Disclosure of Data
Internal and External Third Parties
We may have to share your Personal Data with Internal Third Parties and External Third Parties (as defined below) for the purposes set out in the table above. We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
Internal Third Parties
Other companies in our corporate group acting as joint controllers or processors and who provide IT and system administration services and undertake leadership reporting.
External Third Parties
•Service providers acting as processors who provide IT and system administration services.
Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
•Tax regulators and other authorities who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
•In addition to the parties noted above, we will share Shared Files with others you have chosen to share Shared Files with through the Service.
Business Transaction
If Next Education, LLC is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred to a third party. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your Personal Data in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy.
Disclosure for Law Enforcement
Under certain circumstances, Next Education, LLC may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).
Legal Requirements
Next Education, LLC may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:
•To comply with a legal obligation
•To protect and defend the rights or property of Next Education, LLC
•To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
•To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
•To protect against legal liability
Security of Data
The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
“Do Not Track” Signals
We do not support Do Not Track (“DNT”). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.
You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.
Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
f you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. Next Education, LLC aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.
If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.
In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:
•The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you. Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. We may also not be able to delete Personal Data that is embedded in Shared Files you have chosen to share with others, as described in our Terms of Service.
•The right of rectification. You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.
•The right to object. You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
•The right of restriction. You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.
•The right to data portability. You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
•The right to withdraw consent. You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where Next Education, LLC relied on your consent to process your personal information. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.
You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data; however, if you have an issue about our collection or use of your Personal Data, we kindly ask that you contact us first to give us an opportunity to address your concern. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).
Service Providers
We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.
These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.
Analytics
We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.
•Google Analytics. Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en
Behavioral Remarketing
Next Education, LLC uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.
•Google AdWords. Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: http://www.google.com/settings/ads Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on – https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout – for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en
•Twitter. Twitter remarketing service is provided by Twitter Inc. You can opt-out from Twitter’s interest-based ads by following their instructions: https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405 You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Twitter by visiting their Privacy Policy page: https://twitter.com/privacy
•Facebook. Facebook remarketing service is provided by Facebook Inc. You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950 To opt-out from Facebook’s interest-based ads follow these instructions from Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217 Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA http://www.aboutads.info/choices/, the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada http://youradchoices.ca/ or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/, or opt-out using your mobile device settings.
For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook’s Data Policy: https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation
Payments
We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).
We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, Mastercard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.
Links to Other Sites
Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.
We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.
California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.
Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance
We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.
Online Privacy Policy Only
This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.
Your Consent
By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.
Contacting Us
We have appointed a data protection manager (“DPM”) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the DPM using the details set out below.
Full name of legal entity: Next Education, LLC
Name or title of DPM: Rachel Ito, Marketing Director
Email address: info@animationmentor.com
Postal address: Next Education, LLC, 6040 Hollis St., Emeryville, CA 94608, USA
TAKE AN ONLINE CAMPUS TOUR
Join us for our monthly Online Tour with special guests. Learn More
SIGN UP FOR OUR NEWSLETTER
QUICK LINKS
Character Animation
Maya Workshop
Creature Courses
Animation Characters
Student Showcases
Tuition and Start Dates
Terms of Use   Privacy   Contact Us
© 2005-2021 Next Education LLC. All rights reserved. ANIMATIONMENTOR, ECRITIQUE, AMP, the AnimationMentor logo and other AnimationMentor marks,logo and trade dress are trademarks or registered trademarks of Next Education LLC.
All other trademarks are the property of their respective owners.
